Big Data-

The combination of big data technologies and traditional machine learning algorithms has generated new and interesting challenges in other areas as social media and social networks. These new challenges are focused mainly on problems such as data processing, data storage, data representation, and how data can be used for pattern mining, analysing user behaviours, and visualizing and tracking data, among others.

Recent research has shown that tweets can be used to predict
various large-scale events like elections [3], infectious disease outbreaks
[4], and national revolutions [5]. The essential hypothesis is that the location,
timing, and content of tweets are informative with regard to future
events

: can we use the tweets posted by residents
in a major U.S. city to predict local criminal activity? This is an
important question because tweets are public information and they
are easy to obtain via the official Twitter service. Combined with
Twitter's widespread use around the globe, an affirmative answer to
this question could have implications for a large population of criminal
justice decision makers.For example, improved crime prediction performance
could allow such decision makers to more efficiently allocate
police patrols and officer time, which are expensive and thus scarce for
many jurisdictions.

We pursued three objectives: (1) quantify the crime prediction gains
achieved by adding Twitter-derived information to a standard crime
prediction approach based on kernel density estimation (KDE), (2)
identify existing text processing tools and associated parameterizations
that can be employed effectively in the analysis of tweets for the purpose
of crime prediction, and (3) identify performance bottlenecks
that most affect the Twitter-based crime prediction approach.

Related work
2.1. Crime prediction
Hot-spot maps are a traditional method of analyzing and visualizing
the distribution of crimes across space and time [7]. Relevant techniques
include kernel density estimation (KDE), which fits a two-dimensional
spatial probability density function to a historical crime record. This approach
allows the analyst to rapidly visualize areas with historically
high crime concentrations. Future crimes often occur in the vicinity of
past crimes, making hot-spot maps a valuable crime prediction tool.
More advanced techniques like self-exciting point process models also
capture the spatiotemporal clustering of criminal events [8]. These techniques
are useful but carry specific limitations. First, they are locally descriptive,
meaning that a hot-spot model for one geographic area cannot
be used to characterize a different geographic area. Second, they require
historical crime data for the area of interest, meaning they cannot be constructed
for areas that lack such data. Third, they do not consider the rich
social media landscape of an area when analyzing crime patterns.

Researchers have addressed the first two limitations of hot-spot
maps by projecting the criminal point process into a feature space that
describes each point in terms of its proximity to, for example, local roadways
and police headquarters [9]. This space is then modeled using
simple techniques such as generalized additive models or logistic regression.
The benefits of this approach are clear: it can simultaneously
consider a wide variety of historical and spatial variables when making
predictions; furthermore, predictions can be made for geographic areas
that lack historical crime records, so long as the areas are associated
with the requisite spatial information (e.g., locations of roadways and
police headquarters). The third limitation of traditional hot-spot maps –
the lack of consideration for social media – has been partially addressed
by models discussed in the following section.

The work by Wang et al. comes closest
to the present research by using tweets drawn from local news agencies
[13]. The authors found preliminary evidence that such tweets can be
used to predict hit-and-run vehicular accidents and breaking-andentering
crimes; however, their study did not address several key
aspects of social-media-based crime prediction. First, they used tweets
solely from hand-selected news agencies. These tweets, being written
by professional journalists, were relatively easy to process using current
text analysis techniques; however, this was done at the expense of ignoring
hundreds of thousands of potentially important messages. Second,
the tweets used by Wang et al. were not associated with GPS
location information, which is often attached to Twitter messages and
indicates the user's location when posting the message. Thus, the authors
were unable to explore deeper issues concerning the geographic
origin of Twitter messages and the correlation between message origin
and criminal processes. Third, the authors only investigated two of the
many crime types tracked by police organizations, and they did not
compare their models with traditional hot-spot maps

3. Data collection
Chicago, Illinois ranks third in the United States in population
(2.7 million), second in the categories of total murders, robberies, aggravated
assaults, property crimes, and burglaries, and first in total motor vehicle
thefts (January–June, 2012 [18]). In addition to its large population
and high crime rates, Chicago maintains a rich data portal containing,
among other things, a complete listing of crimes documented by the Chicago
Police Department.1 Using the Data Portal, we collected information
on all crimes documented between January 1, 2013 and March 31, 2013
(n = 60,876). Each crime record in our subset contained a timestamp
of occurrence, latitude/longitude coordinates of the crime at the cityblock
level, and one of 27 types (e.g., ASSAULT and THEFT). Table 1
shows the frequency of each crime type in our subset.

During the same time period, we also collected tweets tagged
with GPS coordinates falling within the city limits of Chicago, Illinois
(n = 1,528,184). We did this using the official Twitter Streaming API, defining
a collection bounding box with coordinates [−87.94011,41.64454]
(lower-left corner) and [−87.52413,42.02303] (upper-right corner).
Fig. 1 shows a time series of the tweets collected during this period and
Fig. 2 shows a graphical KDE of the tweets within the city limits of Chicago.
As shown in Fig. 2, most GPS-tagged tweets are posted in the downtown
area of Chicago.

LDA topic modeling is completely unsupervised, requiring no human
effort to define topics or identify topic probabilities within neighborhoods.
Similar to unsupervised clustering, topics do not have textual labels.
Above, we labeled fi the “airport topic” for explanation purposes
only — such labels do not exist in our models. LDA also does not capture
word order, making each topic an unordered set of words. For our purposes,
the key output of LDA is the probability of each topic in each
neighborhood. We hypothesized that these probabilities would add information
to f1(p) (the historical crime density) by injecting personalized
descriptions from people's everyday lives into the model. 

To predict the occurrence of crime type T, we first defined a onemonth
training window (January 1, 2013–January 31, 2013). We then
put down labeled points (latitude/longitude pairs) across the city limits
of Chicago. These points came from two sources: (1) from the locations
of known crimes of type T within the training window (these points received
a label T), and (2) from a grid of evenly spaced points at 200-
meter intervals, not coinciding with points from the first set (these
points received a label NONE).

